We literally get to put thousands of
dollars in our friends' pockets, and
they get to put thousands of dollars in
our pockets, and it's freaking fun.
>> [music]
>> What's the point of hacking when you can
just, you know, critical thing, right?
All right, hackers, if you're really
looking to take the deep dive this year,
I really recommend you check out the
Critical Thinkers tier in the CTB
Discord, okay? This is the place where
we are doing hack-alongs, AMAs, giving
you exclusive content that only the
inner circle has access to to boost you
as a hacker. Master classes, um, you
know, custom interviews with uh extended
interviews with guests, that sort of
thing. It's a great way to support the
pod, and it's a great way to invest in
yourself as a hacker, and it's a tax
write-off, for sure. So,
give it a shot. Check it out,
ctb.show/discord.
Hope you join us. Thanks.
All right, my guy. 2025 is in the
freaking books, dude. Yes, and you're
going to be hydrating it up today,
right? I am. Yeah, dude. I I just got
over like 2 weeks of being cold. Can or
like can you of being cold? Can you hear
the [laughter] uh can you hear the the
the like raspiness in my voice still or
no? You sound great. Dude, it sounds to
me like I'm like like talking through a
straw or something. It's like it's bad.
Well, I'm going to have to listen to
what you have to say. We've had to push
this back at least once, and Brandon is
also having some Christmas woes, so he
might hop on at some point, but he might
not make it. We'll see.
into the episode live, so we'll see how
that goes. Dude, show them your shirt.
Check out this Critical Thinking merch.
For those of you on YouTube, look at
this. This is the Critical Thinking
Secret Santa 2025 exclusive. We're going
to keep it in the store till a couple
days into January. So, if you're
listening to this episode within the
first like week of it releasing, you can
still get it at ctb.show/swag. Then
we're pulling it forever. So, if you
want the Critical Thinking Secret Santa
T-shirt,
this is the time to get it.
Yeah, dude. Dude, what a year. I feel
like between the mix of AI, bug bounty
taking off, hack bots, this has been the
craziest bug bounty year ever. Yeah,
dude, you picked quite a year to go
full-time bug bounty.
>> [gasps]
>> I did. Yeah, it worked out quite well,
which we'll talk about, but um
but yeah, man, what a time. Cuz like I
feel like there's so much opportunity
around like building products and doing
all kinds of other crazy stuff. And
also, not only first year bug bounty,
but this is the the end of the first
year of me being a co-host. Yeah, man.
Yeah, dude, what a beautiful year. Thank
you so much for coming along on this
journey with me this year, man. It's
like yeah, AI, I mean, obviously like
blowing up. Um, I think dude, you we
were talking a little bit on stats
before the episode. You freaking blew
full-time bug bounty out of the water
this year, man.
Um,
so major congrats for that.
lots of fun collabs, lots of good live
hacking events. Another year living the
dream of of full-time bug bounty, man.
Dude, you got to soak it in. It's so
easy to say onto the next thing.
Yeah, I was just sitting in the hot tub
the other day just thinking about that.
Like, wow,
I'm so blessed to have this job. This
job is literally the best job. If I
could if I could pick a job that I
couldn't pick a job that's better. Like
it just
Dude, let me just remind you guys really
quickly, okay? Like about what our job
is, okay? First, we we get in there, and
we we have the coolest job title ever,
ethical hacker. Like when you're like,
"Oh, at a party," you say, "Yeah, you
know, I'm in cybersecurity or whatever."
And they're like, "Oh, what are you
doing?" And you're like, "Oh, I'm an
ethical hacker, you know?" And they're
like, "What? You're an ethical hacker?"
And then you get that moment of like,
"Wow, people think this job is really
cool, right?" So, excellent job title,
number one, right? Number two, if you're
a full-time bug bounty hunter, you have
complete flexibility. You can work
whenever, wherever, you know, you don't
have to do any sales. Constant demand.
Oh my gosh, it's like unbelievable. You
just show up, you do your thing, you get
money. Yeah.
>> Like and sometimes there's a little bit
of back and forth on the reports or
whatever, but it's nothing compared to
what you would face if you were actually
doing sales or client acquisition.
Right. And this isn't to downplay people
that like that like struggle in bug
bounty. Like they we're clearly talking
about people that are like able to like
make a living with it, right? Full-time
bug hunters or part-time. Like for so
many people, it's a huge blessing. Like
for you or for me at least, and I think
for you, too, like doing it part-time
before we even went full-time, it was
like this this amazing side hustle that
like if you have time to do it, you can
do it, but if you don't, you don't.
Whereas so many other side hustles, it's
like you have to show up, you know what
I mean? And with bug bounty, it's like,
yeah, if you have time to hack, you can
hack, and if you don't, you don't. Yeah,
dude, it's just it's freaking
unbelievable. Then then listen to this,
man. As soon as you as soon as you do
your thing, right, and you hack
something, one, you feel like the
coolest person ever cuz you just did
something you're not supposed to do. You
just outsmarted these, you know,
multi-bill Oh, there's Brandon. Yo, he
hopped in live, just like we said.
Yo.
All right, he might not be able to hear
[__] Hello, chaps. Sorry about that.
It's been like a bit of a whirlwind. All
all good, man. All good. I'm just I'm
just telling the people why they should
be so happy with bug bounty, you know?
Like then, you know, once you find the
vulnerability, right, and you get this
hit of dopamine. You're like, "OH MY
GOSH, I just found it, you know?" Like
and then you're so happy, right? And
then you're banging on the table, right?
And then and then you you you know, you
write up the report, you submit it, and
then you get another crazy dopamine hit
whenever the bounty gets paid, right?
You look at your phone, you see that,
you know, report, you know, reported,
Nothing compares to it. email, you click
the link, and then boom, you know? And
then you're like, "Oh my gosh, yes." And
there's so much dopamine and like
feel-goodness in this job. It's like I
feel like I'm a crack addict sitting
here talking I'm like Then you get to
tell your wife or your friends about the
bounty if you're able to and like you're
in that situation, and then you get to
tell like other bug hunters about the
really cool like finding that you had as
well. Yeah, I mean, and do you go to
your wife and be like, "Hey, honey, I
made another, you know, like say you've
got your you know, Silicon Valley job or
whatever. Hey, honey, another $12,000
this month. Woohoo on my salary." No.
But then you get a bounty for 12 grand,
AND YOU'RE LIKE, "LET'S GO." It feels
special. It feels different. Exactly.
Like, man,
what a freaking beautiful thing, right?
Dude, Brandon, check out the shirt. I
know, sorry for the audio listeners, we
keep talking about it. Look how good
this shirt looks. Dude, Secret Santa.
You see this?
Yeah, see, I just feel so terribly
unprepared. I'm wearing my gym stuff.
Not Christmasy [laughter]
at all. Dude. All right, man. You showed
up. You showed up, right? That's that's
the thing, dude. This December's been a
whirlwind, right? Like we all kind of
talked about prepping for December and
being like, you know, trying to get
Critical Thinking stuff squared away and
like trying to get, you know, all of our
hacking stuff done so that we can like
chill for the last like 2 weeks of
December or whatever.
Then the sickness hit, you know? Yeah,
there's there's no preparing for this
December, unfortunately. No matter what
you done, there's no preparation that
could have fixed it. So, it's one of
those ones, but hey ho, we're all here.
We're recording, that's all that
matters. Exactly. Exactly.
Um
>> [clears throat]
>> Anyway, sorry for for letting that like,
you know, just overflow of gratitude and
passion for the bug bounty world. Dude,
people who are living in dupe land are
going to want to like strangle you.
They're going to be like, "Justin's
bragging about how amazing bug bounty
is. I've gotten six dupes in a row, and
I'm going to go jump off a cliff, you
know?" Like Well, [laughter] let let me
just share this one thing though. Let me
share this, and I know you guys know
what I'm talking about, but like I had
one of the most gutting live hacking
events ever this year. Like I I it was a
new type of scope. I was like, "All
right, I'm going to go after this," you
know, and and I went after it, and I
accomplished exactly what I wanted to
achieve. I got RCE on the thing, right?
And I had like a nice attack vector, and
you know, it was perfectly aligned with
the scope doc,
and it didn't pay. And I made like three
grand on that live hacking event or
something ridiculous like that, right?
And and um
and it was gutting. It was totally
gutting. And and then dude, and then you
know what happened the next freaking day
is I went and went back to my like
uh you know, home program or whatever
and popped like six crits, and it was
like amazing, right? So, this time I
kind of got like, you know, the low kind
of just spiked up, right? But I
definitely understand living in those
lows, too, cuz for a little while after
that live hacking event, I was like,
"Frick, I hate this." You know, like why
can't they just why can't I just do a
job where they give me money for effort,
you know? Yeah.
This is it. The the speaking just as I
joined about the the high highs, right?
That comes with it are the low lows,
where is very much part of part of the
game, and you need to learn to weather
that. Like what personally I felt I know
both of you I've spoken to about this,
about when you're going through a bit of
a hump, and it's not going well. But
then 2 weeks later, forgotten about, is
a distant memory. The bugs are coming
back in, and it's all going fine. Yeah.
You need to have the memory of a
goldfish to be a bug hunter, you know?
Yeah, and that's why I'm so happy.
You just got to you just got to keep
>> [laughter]
>> It's the best I'm so happy.
That's funny.
Um All right. You want to jump to our
questions, Justin? We've got a lot to
go.
>> Yeah, let's get into the meat. This
we're going to save till after, and then
uh but let's go right into the meat. So,
um this will be the second year in a row
of doing this, third year of doing a
similar concept, but um
uh we are kind of going to do a personal
inventory for uh our our hunting. And
Brandon, I know you got stuck in traffic
and got hit with sickness and a bunch of
other things. So, just like try to stick
along as as best you can here with this.
Um true. But what I did last year was I
created like this list of a bunch of
questions that will help you understand
like what your year as a hacker looked
like, and like do some reflection, and
figure out, you know, what you
accomplished, what your best moments
were, what your worst moments were, you
know, did you did you accomplish your
goals? How can you improve as a hacker?
That sort of thing. It's all sort of
bundled in here. We'll release this
again in the hacker notes in conjunction
with this episode.
Um but yeah, The listeners should The
listeners should post like a reflection
like this on like in the Discord or on X
or something. It'd be pretty sweet to
see this from like, you know, our
friends and uh you know, people in the
industry. Yeah, I would love to see it.
Yeah, so that's a great point. If you
can do like a long-form X post or like
even go in the CTBB Discord, maybe we'll
open a channel or something like that.
Yeah. And that says like um
you know, reflections or something like
that. Yeah, that'd be really cool. Yeah.
Yeah. All right. Richard, if you if you
listen to this whole thing, I know this
gets crazy in December, but um we we
would like to open that reflections
channel. So, check it out on the CTBB
Discord or post it on X or both.
Um
All right, let's jump into it. First
question was what moments and bugs were
the most fulfilling to you as a bug
hunter in 2025? Um Reza, why don't you
kick us off there?
Yeah, for some somehow I like copied
that one down and didn't answer it, but
it seems very clear to me what this one
is. Um
I think that like the the best
experience I had was definitely in
Tokyo. Um not to toot your own not toot
your horn too much, but it it felt
magical, right? Like I had never roomed
with a bunch of uh bug hunters cuz I got
into bug bounty hunting after I was
already a family man with kids and
stuff, but
>> Right. like rooming with you and Luke
and Kiron was just like tons of fun. It
felt like being a college again, you
know, just like living with roommates.
And when when I was in college like I
wasn't a hacker, right? So, like living
with roommates who are all also doing
the most exciting thing ever and
competing in like an awesome event. And
then hanging out with all of your, you
know, all of your Japanese friends was
like
>> boys. felt the same way. Like just
staying up late, hanging out with them.
Um and so anyways, yeah, shout out to
them. Shout out to that event. That was
definitely the coolest moment. I would
say more more like the the the proud
moments were, you know, kind of those
like high-paying, really impactful bugs.
You know, one I had on Amazon was just
like incredible and you know, got the
best best bug of the latest IPC, Amazon
IPC. Those are those are the moments
that I was like, you know, probably the
most proud of. So.
Very nice, man. Very nice. Um
Brendan, uh
what about you? What is your like, you
know, best moment or most fulfilling
bug?
>> moment. Or proudest moments. You can
mention more than one.
I
So, the one that comes to mind now that
I actually think I told either of you
this, but it was I think it was in April
in Seattle for one of the smaller IPCs.
Um
I went there, gave it 100%, and then
towards the end of the event, there was
absolute magic happening. Like just
absolute magic. I won I think I won my
first Was that my first award? I'm
pretty sure I won my first award and won
numerous awards that event. And um
I was on a I was on a hacker's high.
It's my first time in Seattle. I done
like a lot of things I didn't think were
mentally possible.
On a target, overcome
overcome the
overcome the scaries a little bit. And
then as a reward on the flight back, I
checked if I could be upgraded, and I
could, and I flew back business
>> No, you didn't, dude.
Nice. Man, that feeling. I mean, that
was like you can't recreate that. That
because the the event was like this, and
then it finished up here, and then I
finished the whole trip coming back
flying business. I was like this this is
it. I don't know what this is, but this
is it. And that for me was like one of
those moments where it just felt good.
>> Frickin' ugly got to you, man. Yeah, no
joke. Yeah, I don't really care. It's
like
a couple hours on the plane, who cares?
But we're like what? I mean, I'm like
5'10, you're like what? 6 ft maybe?
Reza?
>> 6'3. Oh, yeah, I'm 5'11, yeah. You're
5'11, yeah, so and then you're 6'3,
Brendan. Yeah, it's a different
experience. I know like I'm
Like for me now I've done it, I'm not
too fussed about it, but it's one of
like the whole thing was the experience,
right? I was just started off full-time
in bug bounty. It was like my first
event where I felt like I had something
to prove personally because I was fresh
in bug bounty and I really wanted to do
well. Like personally, I really wanted
to do well. And then there's parts of
the event where it wasn't going well,
and then I powered through that. I went
really well.
And much better than anyone could
imagine. That's when I was like, you
know what?
Let's give it a go. And then like it was
a lot of
small personal things of like new
experiences, and it all just come
together to make a really like personal
achievement for myself.
>> Beautiful, man. Beautiful, man. And I
think for me this year, like there were
so many amazing moments of hacking.
Um the Tokyo event was lovely getting in
that Airbnb with the boys and like
getting around the table and just like,
you know, hacking it out.
>> that's near and dear to your heart,
right? I'm sure that's also good. Yeah.
That was awesome. And and um and then
uh yeah, I mean, and also just like last
time I think I talked about this on the
pod near there, but like last live
hacking event in Tokyo, it was was a
PayPal event, which was like an event
that I like I I a a target that I was
pretty comfortable with, you know, and I
was like, all right, I'm going to really
crush this. And then I totally flopped,
right? And and wasn't even in the top
10, which is almost never happens to me.
And and I was gutted by that, right? And
then um so, it feels good to like come
back and like take the MBH in in Tokyo.
Um
The other moments I had on here was
hacking with Frans and Matias in Sweden.
Um just like, you know, working with
those guys is amazing. Uh you know, and
and then um
Yeah, the other one was seeing the stars
align on that one New Relic bug that I
talked about at the end of the Halloween
episode. Like that was just one of those
moments where I'm just sitting here at
my desk like almost shaking with like I
cannot believe that happened. I cannot
believe this worked. I've got the token.
It's over. GG, you know, like and and uh
and so, yeah, man. I just like those are
those are some crazy crazy memories for
me this year. So, I mean and and okay,
the next question here was like, were
these moments when you found the bug or
when you got the bounty or who you were
working with, right? And I think for me
um it was a it was a lot of both, you
know, like it was largely collaboration
and and um you know, seeing the
vulnerabilities line from a technical
perspective, but I also have on here as
one of my favorite moments popping a
six-figure bounty, right? Um which was
the first six-figure bounty I've ever
done, right? So, it's like it's got for
me, I'm really like balanced out across
the three, you know, main
components I think of like what makes a
meaningful experience as a bug bounty
hunter, which is, you know, technical
like victory, uh you know,
collaboration, and um and you know,
>> Exactly, financial, right? Like getting
your bounties. Um so, I don't know. What
are your guys' thoughts on like which
which one is most gratifying for you?
>> [snorts]
>> I think for me like when you ask me,
it's easy to like look back and like
view them all together like in
retrospect.
Yeah.
>> Um yeah.
I think maybe just when it popped. Like
when yeah, for me just like when the
when that Amazon bug popped, like just
being really proud of that one.
I yeah. I think that actually
I don't know. There's something really
insane about not feeling imposter
syndrome. And in that moment, you get
like the complete opposite. It's like
>> Yeah. I'm a beast, you know? Like you
just like you feel awesome. You feel
like you're like a football player in
the stadium like an NFL player just like
screaming at the camera. Like that's the
moment that I feel like is like makes it
all worth like worth it, you know?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, agree.
It's hard for me to say because it's
been obviously we're coming up as of a
week, 1 year since I started full-time
bug bounty. And it has been such a rich
learning experience going full-time. Um
especially cuz I only done bug bounty
part-time for a year before. So, like
there's so many good parts to it that
just unexpected things that I didn't
think that would happen. Like collabing
with both of you throughout targets this
year has been great. Collabing with some
other friends like Access Doctor, ads,
like all of these things and events. It
has been such a rich learning experience
and has like helped me grow personally
as well as a hacker.
Yeah, I don't know. There's
I would Is it possible to just say like
2025 as a year has just been
unbelievable? [laughter] I guess it
isn't.
It really has been great. I just find it
hard to like really nail it down cuz
yeah, it's been it's been explosive in
terms of the learning experience, the
personal barriers, and things I think
I've overcome both technically and
mentally to be able to do it full-time.
And
yeah, it's just been insane. I have a
similar rant to Justin's rant about how
awesome bug bounty is about
collaboration that I want to get to when
I get to that section. Oh, hell yeah.
Hell yeah. I'm looking forward to that.
Okay. So, um
that that kind of wraps the the first
two. And then we're going to jump into
looking back on your 2025 bug bounty
performance.
Were you satisfied with? And then we'll
go through the list, right? So, for me,
number of bugs, I landed at 104 uh bugs
this year.
Um
and it was kind of hard to calculate
this year because it was like uh across
HackerOne. Like I used to do largely
HackerOne. So, I'd like sum up all my
HackerOne ones and then like grab a
couple from over here. But like this
year I hacked a lot on Google, hacked a
lot on HackerOne, did some Bugcrowd, you
know, it was it was a little bit more
all over the place. But I landed at
around 104, and I'm pretty pleased with
that. I think that's a good a good
volume. Um I think last year I said I
wanted to do more, uh but I also said I
wanted to get more criticality, and I
think I did get more criticality um this
year. So, overall, landing at 104, I'm
pretty pleased with that.
Mhm. Yeah, I had exactly 100. I was kind
of surprised it was a round number.
Um
and I thought it was like funny that it
was so similar to yours, Justin. Um
which is interesting cuz I think that my
average payout is probably slightly
less, and I had more diversified income.
Mhm. Um but if you take out your outlier
of your six-figure bug, it's like I
wonder if they'd be kind of similar.
Probably.
>> Um
but also I I I find it more uh
interesting because I think of you as
more of a critical like a like a person
who finds a higher criticality of bugs
than me on average. But I think that the
bonuses and um and live hacking events
played into my payouts a lot. Like I
think that my actual finding, if you
remove the bonuses and live hacking
events inflated bounties, then I
probably would have like a lower
criticality score overall. Um I did pull
my average impact from HackerOne, which
is obviously lifetime, and it's like
22.85 or something, which I felt like
pretty good about.
>> Yeah, that's that's a good impact. What
Brendan, I know you don't have all the
stats right in front of you, but do you
do you know roughly how many bugs you
got?
Yeah, yeah. Um so, I came in just over
160 across all the platforms.
>> Wow, look at this guy. Look at this guy.
So, so and like
I did want to spend a little bit of time
speaking about this cuz obviously,
naturally you want to go for that impact
as a hunter, but I found very naturally
and as a natural byproduct of going
full-time, I got on the mindset of like
I am reporting everything that has a
meaningful attack vector
and like I don't care what it is. I'm
reporting it and I'm going to argue this
variant and blah blah blah. It doesn't
matter to me anymore. This is like my
living
and my lifeblood. So, I would say it's a
byproduct of that mindset a bit more cuz
if I was part-time, I'll definitely hold
on to bugs for a lot longer and maybe
even forget to report them. I'm looking
through my notes. I have literal bugs
there which I just haven't reported.
Like loads. So, this year's definitely
been a No, it doesn't matter what it is.
Get it in, report it. So, I'd say that
is a byproduct of that mindset a bit
more. Yeah, my number is not based on me
trying to only report highs and crits. I
have reported everything. So, you just
put in more work than me. I I'm not a
snob about that and I am of the same
mind as Brandon. I think bug hunters
should report everything.
You know, obviously maybe not like open
redirect lows and stuff like that, but
in general like if you find medium
pluses and they have any kind of
security impact, I'm a big fan of
recommending people reporting them.
Yeah.
I just pulled my
my stats here.
Um as far as severity distribution and
just assuming HackerOne is like a
representative, you know, of all the
samples. Probably less criticals on
Google, I'd imagine, but um this one has
my critical severity sitting at um ratio
sitting at 15%. 30 for highs, uh 40 for
mediums, 12 for lows, and then three uh
none.
Um so, yeah, I'm pretty pleased with
that. I think that's I think that's
pretty solid. Also, I just asked High
with the HackerOne AI thing to generate
that stat like this that pie chart for
me to look at and it like one-shotted
it, which I'm very pleased with. I think
that's pretty cool.
>> Okay. So, so you got these stats from
High cuz I've been
Okay.
>> So, go to go to performance on the
HackerOne dashboard, click the little
explore High insights at the top and ask
for a severity distribution pie pie
graph and it'll just generate it for
you.
I I went to I went to the dashboard and
then down in performance and you can
just kind of build your own.
>> [snorts]
>> And it looks like
um Oh, I think that it does submissions
though, Justin, not including collabs.
So, I will may at least mine's showing
without collabs. Okay.
>> So, if you So, if you exclude collabs,
my ratio Oh, it doesn't have percentages
though. Oh, man. Yeah, I need to just
use High like you all did. Nice. Yeah.
Yeah, I think High's pretty solid for
this. Um I am going to look at my
lifetime
uh my impact for the past 90 days is 25.
My lifetime impact is at 20. So, you
said your lifetime impact is at 22?
Yeah, 22, yeah. That's sick. That's
good. Well, you've been you've been
you've also been hacking for When did
you start hacking?
Um it's been like five or six years,
yeah. Five years? Yeah. Yeah, I just
went to my I just went to my profile and
changed it to all time.
And I have like a yeah.
22 actually 22.27.
I would say my stats from the last 90
days have taken a bit of a beating from
the event which I will not we shall not
speak about. It went to the floor and it
pains me every time I see this stuff,
but um all time is 21.5, so it's okay,
but it has gone down. Nice, nice.
>> Yeah, that's sick. I wonder I I
anticipate
like I I'd have to do some additional
stat magic to try to figure this out,
but I know back in the day when I was a
recon boy, I was submitting like just
tons of lows and mediums. Well, yeah,
you also did like subdomain takeovers
and all that. If you set it to last
year, what's the impact?
Uh it's on your profile. On on
uh uh past year. Oh, there's past year.
Nice. That's nice. 22. So, similar.
Okay. Sweet. Um
what kind of bugs do you think are kind
of fueling your hacking?
Hm.
Wow, I can tell you that my
submissions is like looks like a rainbow
and this very much comes down to I spoke
about on the previous episode, but like
I this thing in my head like know your
target and like once you get a feel for
the target and you sort of feel it out
and have an idea, I just try to adapt to
what I think will be vulnerable for the
scope I'm looking at. So, like
I'm very adaptive, I'd say, to my target
cuz I want to find bugs no matter what,
so I try to adapt for that as much as
possible.
So, my mine's all over the place is a
short answer. Literally everything.
Every type of XSS, CSRF, cache
poisoning, business logic errors, broken
access control, prompt injection, like
it's literally information disclosure,
like SSRF, everything.
Hm.
My boy. That That's awesome, dude.
That's like I mean, yeah, that that
shows how eclectic you are as a hacker,
right? Um and how how able to adjust to
the target you are. I think largely for
me, it was a lot of IDOR,
a lot of RCE, a lot of business logic. I
get Okay, a lot of RCE relatively,
right?
A lot of RCE.
>> Yeah, you know, a lot of RCE. [laughter]
Um you know, uh
XSS, auth bypasses, privilege
escalations, that sort of thing. I don't
know that I found a bunch of like
caching bugs this year, maybe like one
or two. Um definitely CSRF um and CSBT
and like, you know, that sort of whole
flow. Um but I would say largely like
I mean, like um the IDORminator, right,
that's been coming back on on Twitter
has been saying Yeah, Zwinck. A lot of
freaking IDOR bugs, dude. Like just
being thorough, being deep, testing
those out, getting some AI assistance,
you know, on that nowadays as well.
Um
really valuable, I think.
Yeah, for me, I would say it was mostly
like probably honestly 40% AI bugs and
then
the rest were kind of split among IDOR,
CSRF, info disclosure, business logic,
like that sort of thing, but yeah,
definitely a ton of AI bugs, but a lot
of that is just a byproduct of what I
was invited to. Like I think that
you like like Brandon was saying, it's
ideal to roll with the punches and I
think for me, I've always been as
pragmatic as I could from a hacking
perspective.
And so, I think that you know, I got a
lot of brand new invites that were
AI-related programs and so it's like of
course I'm going to go look at bugs on
those. And so,
uh yeah, that's how it kind of played
out for me. Um and I think I think we're
kind of supposed to be talking about
whether we were satisfied with each of
these things, right? And so, I I I think
it's whether I'm satisfied with those, I
would say yeah. I mean, the year went
great. It's hard to be negative about
that.
Um
and I think that it is kind of crazy.
Maybe IDOR is just live forever.
Yeah. I mean, I I I think so and I think
they're they're I mean, as a full-time
hunter, it makes sense, right? Like you
clean up the IDOR scope and then you
focus on something more like, you know,
technically depthful, right? I would I
am satisfied with this overall. I think
for me, I would like more RCE and I
would like more uh SSRF and I would like
more um arbitrary file write and read.
Uh I think that those would be pretty
valuable and I think every time I've
gone deeper and tried to look at like
um you know,
some areas where there are possibilities
for that sort of thing. It's like that.
Yeah, yeah. I think I just need to do
that, you know, more often. So, I'm
going to continue doing that. And and I
made improvement on that this year and I
think I will continue to make
improvement on that in the future.
Yeah, 100%.
Um I have very mixed emotions about mine
because part of me is like just start
hammering that impact. Like last year
when I went through the incredible SSRF
run, like I I was feeling good. The
impact was there, but it wasn't my I
wasn't full-time. So, now the mindset
has completely changed around that and
what matters to me more is around it
being more sustainable rather than going
after that. And like
personally,
compared to start of this year to to
now, the like skill set improvements
that I've had and the scope that I'd
feel comfortable looking at and like the
collabs that I feel comfortable doing,
I feel like it has just been such a rich
experience and like you can kind of see
that a little bit from the stats and and
the the bug class I have reported per
quarter. But I would say that there's
been like massive technical improvements
as well for me. This year has been
insane. So,
part of me is like, you can't probably
could have done better, but then the
other part is like relatively speaking,
you done well at your first year. You
done a lot outside of bug bounty as
well, so be grateful for that. Dude, you
know, you all shared with me the numbers
for your years in in total before this
this call and I'm just blown away by
y'all's like first year performance as
full-time hunters. Holy crap, you guys.
Like absolutely unbelievable. I did do
some analysis based off of like the
HackerOne
um powered security report thing and um
all of us land in the top 2% and one of
us lands in the top 1% for hackers. So,
guys, like let just let me understand,
you know, to the listener, like these
guys are awesome at this, right? Like we
we we are all at the top of this 1% of
bug bounty hunters. Um and we're we're
going to keep it that way with hosts for
this podcast. Like if if anybody is
going to be coming on here and hosting
the podcast, they need to be as a
prerequisite, I mean, at least top 5%
bug bounty hunter in my opinion.
Um so, anyway, I just I just, you know,
without patting ourselves on the
>> Justin says that with his personality
type, not bragging. He says that because
he wants to provide you with by far the
best information and he cares deeply
about making sure that we provide that
for you guys and that we are like
you know, people who are technically
strong and so that was a part of
Justin's interview process and so yeah,
I think that he cares so deeply about
that. Exactly and and I you know, it
essential for for critical thinking's
brand as well, I believe like to
understand that you have to be doing it
like
let me just tell you it is very hard to
create content and also be in the top 1%
for something, right? So
really good like and I've had a little
bit of practice now over the past couple
years, right? You guys did it your first
freaking year like that is badass and
I'm so proud of you guys.
So really good job.
Um. Thank you very much. All right, so
going back to the list here.
What
are you guys satisfied with the scope
that you hacked on the programs that you
hacked on and the quality of your
reports?
I I do think that it's hard to know if
you're making the right decision any
moment in time. You know, looking back I
think it clearly worked out but you
know, hindsight's 20/20. I guess maybe
not though cuz I don't really know what
decisions I I made that I could have
made differently but I do always
second-guess myself with like man, do I
have a good anchor program? What would a
better anchor program be? What should I
be hacking on because we have so much
opportunity not just from like I mean
even if you weren't any private
programs, there are so many public
programs and so many of them like
actually do pay well like whether it's
Google or meta or whatever like there's
like lots of good programs out there.
That's a hard question to to answer
about whether I'm satisfied in that
regard like it's very hard to know what
to be hacking on
but as far as
the scope yeah, I think the ASF was a
good decision both getting into it
initially and then continuing to press
into it and I think quality of reports
just having like AI be able to like help
you throw together reports to write them
much faster. It's really helped me. So
I'm super happy with quality super happy
with scope. Programs is a harder is a
harder answer for me. Yeah, yeah, that
makes sense Brandon.
Yeah, I would agree so I've done quite a
few events this year so that has driven
the scope I've looked at to an extent.
What I would say is I would probably
like to have
one more program on rotation that I
regularly go back and look at that I'm
in tune with. I know roughly when they
do that development. I know where to
find documentation like I that I'm very
much in tune with. I'd like one more of
those cuz I feel like that would be
quite beneficial. How many do you have?
I have two. Two? Two right now. I did
have another one but then
I sort of gone off of it so
I'd like three titles that I can rotate
through
consistently and have that on so that
definitely would be a bigger goal for me
next year.
Other than that I would say in hindsight
it was as best it could be. Yeah,
I I want to say I have three base
programs and they're actually all public
so I can talk about them all. They're
Google, Epic and Capital One.
Um and feels good man. I mean I think
three
>> I'm at basically like zero. Like for me
it's like kind of Google kind of Google
but I don't really like come back to it
consistently in the way you do. So I
think that that should be a goal for
mine is to like pick you know, two or
three.
>> Two. No anchor program and you earned
that dude. You crushed it this year man.
You
that is sick.
Um.
Yeah, I think as far as quality of
reports goes Google has a
report quality bonus that they give out
and just being like financially
incentivized to do that build some good
habits for me I think that I even found
transferring to other programs.
So shout out to Google for like
building the whole ecosystem like
encouraging hackers to write better
reports in general by their report bonus
and I think that definitely um
that definitely helped me this year. As
an outsider who saw you do that I just
want to say to the audience cuz I think
it's like a really good technical tip.
Justin almost always records a video for
any high plus vulnerability and also
spends way more time on POCs than I
think most people do. Like
I would say you know, when you're doing
when you're doing bug bounty like you
know, most people will throw together a
POC or have an okay one maybe but on
some of our reports like specifically
thinking about the Google Tokyo event
Justin put in hours on a POC to make it
realistic looking and I think it
probably 5x the bounty. Like it it was a
bug actually to be honest it might have
went from unpaid to paid as a higher
critical legitimately just because of
the quality of the POC and so I think
that that is like probably a really
great takeaway. Yeah, yeah, I I know the
report you're talking about and and like
it was a hard call and and thank you
guys for standing by me with that you
know, in the live hacking event for me
to spend you know, three hours putting
together a POC in the middle of the live
hacking event the day before you know,
the competition, right?
But it it did it did work out this time
and I have in my notes here that I think
like now I am addressing root cause
and and suggesting fixes in my reports
which I think is good.
I think I still let the POC and POC
video do a little bit too much talking
you know, for for my report. Like I
think I could probably explain things
from like a technical perspective in
text better. Um. Yeah, it's very
frustrating when a triager comes in and
asks a question that you answered
clearly in your video and you're like I
should have just put it in text. Yeah,
exactly exactly. So I think if I can
just get that video and you know,
hopefully I think I think that is the
most impactful thing, right? Like POC or
GTFO like if you can provide a good POC
and a POC video the impact and the
you know, methodology should explain
itself to most technical people, right?
But I think because there are so many
layers that go into bug bounty like
triage you know, people that are
creating the tickets you know, then the
devs then the security team you know, it
does help to have it in text as well and
just hit it from all angles.
Sweet. I didn't have anything else there
Brandon.
>> [snorts]
>> No, I think I've always been
from the reporting side okay
anything medium is like my 80% and then
anything high and critical is the video
the full works. This is why this is why
I given it the CVSS metric. This is why
it affects integrity and things like
that. So
I would say
the report effort does coincide with the
report severity too. So
that's just a bit of the meta strategy I
have though. I like explaining the CVSS.
I've done that with programs that have
like high CVSS correlation, right? Where
it's like okay, they pay by the book for
CVSS which one of my anchor programs
does.
So yeah, I think that's a good call and
I imagine you get a lot higher
a lot less back and forth because of
that.
Exactly. What I would say I've recently
went on the pod and spoke about this is
that CVSS and AI fundamentally doesn't
work. It's not fit for purpose so don't
do that for an AI bug cuz you will get
screwed 10 times out of 10 every single
time. So if you're traditional web and
mobile and things like that that's okay
but not AI AI.
It requires too much user interaction
and yeah and the impact is often one
user, right? So it's tough but like you
know, like we've we've pushed for in the
past you know, it's it's a new skill set
it's a new domain you know, we recommend
programs like trying to pay it well.
Yeah, I did want to share something
anecdotally about that though cuz we did
the episode with Sassy, right? Which I
would recommend you all go back and
listen to if you haven't. I know that we
do a lot of AI stuff but this is really
going to be pivotal.
You know, in no more security on the
Gemini Jack thing and
I watched the episode and of course you
know, recorded the episode and and it
was very interesting
you know, to see the approach that he
that he went through and make to make it
zero click, right? Where it's just the
users just asking their normal workflow
and then they get owned.
And then
you know, it caused and obviously people
are going to go into Gemini and ask like
hey you know, can you summarize this for
me, right? But I have to say for the
first time
like last week I actually did that
myself. Like I went into Gemini and said
hey, check my email and create an
itinerary for this trip, right? That I
that I that I already booked all the
stuff. I just want an itinerary. And you
thought I could have just got zero
clicked. Yeah, and then and then as I
press enter I'm like [__] Like that
this looks like the beginning of a POC
video. You know, like and and but but I
think that validates, right? That
validates the attack vector that like as
a user I just did that, right? And you
know, maybe we're the most tech forward
bunch but everybody's going to be doing
that in like a year, you know, if
they're not already. Um. So Exactly. I
feel like that needs to mature a bit
from triager side and also internal
program knowledge side because I
I've personally had so much friction
around like okay, you are using CVSS for
this but that is like normal user
interaction. So do you set UI required
or like where does the scope change in
in this context? So Yeah, there needs to
be a new there needs to be something new
there but I I firmly believe
I firmly believe that if you're not
coming to an attacker controlled site
and you're performing a an action that
normal users would do with normal use of
the application then that is not UI
required. I think we need a blog post
for that or or something. We need we
we need something that's a blog post
about that on both scope and UI. I think
scope and UI for CVSS on AI bugs it'd be
really nice to have like a reference
doc. Yeah, you're the blog guy dude. You
got to I will yeah, yeah, no, I'll do a
post on this. I like it. Do it. I got to
stand up for my boys.
Yeah, I think
I think one of the interesting thing
that I realized this year as well with
my NahamCon talk. I really enjoyed that
talk and I would really recommend the
listeners go check it out. Um.
But I I hate doing talks bro. Like I I
hate prepping slides. Like I I hate it.
>> to no end and then cram it at the last
day. And I I think it's so funny how I
can come on here on the pod and talk for
you you an hour hour and a half every
week, and like give no lilies, and like
just like not bother me at all, right?
And and then like if I have to prep
slides and do a talk on it, like giving
the talk itself is not a problem. Like I
love giving the talk. But like prepping
the slides for a talk is like the worst.
So I think I I've decided I'm never
going to do it again.
Sorry? I think I've decided I think I'm
never going to do it again. I think I
don't have to do it.
I think I I I have I have money, I have
time, I have like I have a podcast, I
produce content. I don't have to give a
talk ever again. I think you should I
think you should just do a live talk.
Basically, just do a live podcast. Like
you can be like, "Hey, I'll get up
there. I'll do panels. You can even tell
You can even ask me questions about the
bugs that you want me to talk about. You
can do hosting." So I think that's fine.
I love it. I really love radical
decisions around lifestyle design. And
if this is something that you've decided
that you just don't love, don't ever do
it again. I just hate it. And and and
and you know, the thing is maybe I'll do
a little like recording or something
like that, and I'll just pay somebody to
go prep the slides or whatever. I just
hate it.
Exactly, you know? And and but I just
realized I hate it. And and like and I
don't want to spend my time doing it.
And looking back at this past year,
the the times that I've been most
stressed are when I'm doing that.
And I and I just like and and like
literally and like that says a lot,
right? You you preakers know my year
that I've had, right? And and probably
I've had a stressful year in lots of
other ways. But like
easily top top five, three of them are
are prepping slides. I don't know why. I
don't I don't understand how the
security industry has ran off of
conferences for so long, because I feel
the exact same way, Justin. And it's
crazy to me that so many people will
spend like weeks or months doing
research, weeks doing slides, and then
they go to a conference and speak for
speak in front of 10 people. I'm like,
"Holy crap." People like
don't realize the amount of effort that
goes into people's talks that then get
no reach. I just also feel like my
slides look like [__] You know, that's
the other thing. Is like I spend a lot
of time like and maybe AI will fix this,
you know, in the next year, hopefully.
And I know Gamma's already doing some
good stuff with this. But um I also feel
like I get to the end of it, and I'm
like, "Wow, this looks bad." You know,
like and I and you know, for me as a
hacker, I just like, "You know what?
Actually, I don't give a shit." You
know, like I'm just going to present it.
Like it gets the content across. It
helps the people. That's the goal,
right? It's not We're not like, you
know,
freaking giving a
you know,
talk to pitch people for an investment
or something. You know, like Um but
yeah, I think I think either I'm just
going to not do it, or I'm going to have
somebody else make the slides, and then
I'll deliver the talk. And and that'll
be what it is. And what what Brandon,
what what you're giving me [__] for
this. Why are you giving me [__]
>> No, I'm no no no no no. I'm not giving
you any stick at all. I I respect it as
a friend, but I'm upset because I know
how much people in the community loves
the stuff you do, and how much of like a
of a pillar you are. Because when you do
a talk, people listen. That's why I'm a
big guy. But as a friend, I respect it.
They just got to tune into the
hackalongs to keep listening to the pod,
right? Well, that's it, man. Yeah. Well,
that's the other thing. Is like I don't
want to not give back to the community.
So I will do podcasts, right? You know?
I just don't like the visual piece of
it. Like creating the like I'm I'm not
very visually creative in general,
actually. I think this is like a a
personal We're getting really off topic
here. But I think this is like a
personal weakness for me is like, you
know, I can't draw. Like like everything
artistically that I do is is like music,
right? Um
and so like no no drawing, no painting,
no you know, even like design, right?
Like design of like interior design or
or even like right, I do real estate
renos, right? I completely blindly trust
my wife with that. Like I I say,
"Mariah, tell me what we're doing here."
And then she does it she tells me, and
then I go make it happen, right? Um and
it looks great every time, which is
great, you know? And she's got my back
there. Um but I think just visually like
I think that's a weakness. And so yeah,
I think when I'm trying to work from
this area that's a weakness,
it stresses me out, and it doesn't get
good result. And so that those are the
things you should kick out of your life.
Yeah. Right? Yeah. I mean, yeah. Uh just
before we move on, I completely agree.
And I when I obviously done the
hackanotes, Yuji would like look at my
templates and like look at my stuff, and
he's like,
"How do you work with this? It doesn't
look good." And I'm like, "Mate, I'm not
in the business of making stuff look
good at all. It's
far beyond my comprehension or ability.
So please, if you want to do that, do
that, but I'm focusing on content.
Um I'm in the same boat as you, mate.
>> I do want to gas up our man Brandon
here, though. From a talks perspective,
2025 brought him a lot of inbound and
and boosted his personal brand. So talks
can also do wonders for things.
Obviously, Justin, you have the personal
brand. Whereas Brandon [snorts] is
building his up right now, but I think
that like you know, they can still be
very powerful. Yeah.
Yeah, Brandon used them to great
to great What's the word there? To great
effect in in 2025. And I think that's
really cool. Yeah. I'll take it. Yeah, I
I totally agree there. And I think I'm
going to miss giving talks, right? Like
if if I don't find a good solution to
have somebody make slides, then I I'm
going to miss giving talks, cuz I love
giving talks. Giving talks is the best,
you know? And and like especially like
when you're giving them live. Like I
will say it makes sense, right? Like
maybe we should just upload the talk to
YouTube and not instead of giving them
in a room of 20 people. But it's also
pretty sick when you're in the room with
like, you know, all right, let's call it
50 people or 100 people, and you got
your mic'd up, you got your slides
behind you, you're talking about
something you're really passionate
about. You're walking through the crowd,
you know, talking to people and and
like, you know, explaining things and
like, you know, transferring that energy
out. You know, we we kind of get spoiled
cuz we get to do that every week on the
pod, right? But but you know, being
there in person, I think definitely does
have a little bit of a different aspect
to it. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> [snorts and clears throat]
>> Yeah, 100%. Okay. Okay. Okay. We got we
got super way off topic here. But
let's let's hit these pretty quickly.
Okay, we've got 30 minutes. We're good.
Are you happy with your current level of
automation, organization, collaboration?
Who's starting?
Uh let's let's start with you, Brandon.
Me? Okay. So automation, um
you both probably know that I'm slowly
and I'm not talking like full-scale
automation. I'm more talking about
workflow automation.
Um I've upped that. I went from nothing
to something this year, and that for me
came in the form of JavaScript
monitoring.
And that's now I would consider in quite
a good spot, quite a powerful spot. I
say I integrated, and it's actually
feeding me leads which are actionable.
Um so I'm happy on that front, and I'm
not an automation guy.
Um and I've also spent a lot of time
vibe coding a lot of things. So
if it wasn't for vibe coding, I would
have nothing. I will probably say that.
Shoot out of like I just couldn't bring
myself to do it, cuz I know I could be
hacking and making more money. But vibe
coding's very like it's a vibe, as the
name suggests. It's good. It's fun. It's
it's frictionless almost.
So I'd say yes on the automation,
definitely getting there.
The organization
solely, and I mean solely held together
by my notes and my note structure. That
is it. That is probably the the only
organization I have in my life. Um
so yes, I'd say better on that. What And
here's something I do want to talk to
you to about. What I found is though
that completely goes out of the window
in a live event. I don't know what it
is. I'm like I'm more frantic in a live
event, and I use my I use my notepad
more, but not my notion more. Do in a
live event, do you guys take notes, or
how Yeah, I I take notes
I don't want to say almost exclusively
at live hacking events, but like Same.
kind I'm on way way more during events
for me. Mhm. Yeah. So what
Yeah, see, it's different for me. I take
I I take note of like the gadget or
weird behavior, but I don't take a lot
of the context, if that makes sense. So
like they're very brief and nowhere near
as concise as my main as my main
notions. I've noticed in your notion
stuff, you you you take a lot of detail
notes like about the stack and stuff
like that, too. I think for me this
year, I'm going to be spending I'm going
to be pushing a lot of that to AI,
because Kaito Kaito shift agents like
dude, I was blown away. Like I mentioned
this in the talk, but like I ran a
research agent from from Kaito on a
target that I is one of my core targets,
and an API I'm very familiar with, and
it like pulled three or four insights
that I did not know about, you know, and
correlated things. And I was like, "Oh,
wow, that's that's very insightful,
actually." And and
And so I'm definitely going to be using
shift agents
to to like do that sort of research and
note taking in the future, and then take
those learnings, right? Cuz it'll create
learnings in its system, and just export
those to notes.
Yeah, that's that's really nice. I think
I'm going to explore that a bit more.
Whereas I feel like you've always got
some nice little like something I don't
know workflow-wise. Like the FF
masterclass, I was just taken back by
how much of a noob I was. And like all
these other little AI things I always
consult you on in terms of workflow. So
I feel like you're doing something
there. Well, the audience doesn't know
that I gave you that little masterclass.
That's funny. I have done a meeting with
Brandon and like walked him through how
to use FF you have the right way.
So that was kind of fun. But
no, honestly, so my answer to this is
no. I've not been doing enough of it. I
think I I did less this year than I've
ever done, and I'm really sad about it,
cuz I feel like I'm the hack by guy, and
I have people like J B how they're using
Cloud Code to he's been using Cloud Code
to find tons of bugs. And Justin, you
know, did the shift agents talk and
research, and I'm like jealous of it,
too. So, you know, I'm I'm I'm resting
in my contentment. I think this is
incredible year both, you know, with my
young kids, even though we've had a
crazy year as well, and then also, you
know, professionally. But no, yeah, my
answer to this question is I'm not happy
with with my automation. I want to do
much more of it. I think that
Whoop.
I dropped I dropped my ring.
I think that there's a much more
capability for people to do that now
with live coding which I really really
enjoy and so I think that I should build
more automation in that way and more
hackbot automation. I think that
Kaito and shifter are like the best
place ever to be able to find some
insane bugs.
Organization I've been fine on and
collaboration I have
Yeah, collaborated maybe
a lot in the earlier part of the year
and then less in the later part of the
year and I had this light bulb moment
that I wanted to mention. I think I
messaged Justin when it when it when it
first had this light bulb moment but I
think that there is a desire to you know
be personally awesome and I think that
you know all hackers go through that
desire you know to like fight back
imposter syndrome and to feel awesome
and to like you know really pursue MBH
and
I don't know. I think that the pursuit
of that I basically have had like maybe
let's say three or four events over the
last two years where I was like nope,
I'm going to go solo. I'll do some maybe
some like light collaboration with
people if like it makes sense like one
off. My goal is to be solo and in every
one of those I left way less satisfied
with the results and way I feel like I
was under motivated in them even though
the whole point of doing it that way was
to be more motivated and so I think that
I am just the type of person who is more
energized and more motivated which I
know I'm an extrovert right but I think
that I actually have seen that play out
in my life so many times now that I'm
going to always pursue collaboration and
I think that it is an incredible aspect
of our industry in the fact that like we
literally get to put thousands of
dollars in our friends pockets and they
get to put thousands of dollars in our
pockets and it's freaking fun and I'm
learning way more and I'm getting filled
up and enjoying it way more and that
maybe that matters maybe more than we
can even tangibly you know understand
because like that affects how much you
want to do it that night and how much
you want to do it the next day and how
much you like you know you're talking
about it with your friends the next week
right and I think that collaboration
allows you to talk about leads which are
really interesting and fun to talk about
and when you're solo and you don't get
to share those like those little pieces
of quirky behavior with others you know
maybe you do once the due period's over
right or maybe you do the next week or
maybe you do at some point but I think
like sharing those as they occur kind of
can create more hype and more fuel like
to the fire that makes it more exciting
and more fun and it definitely ends up
in way more bugs for me personally. I
know that like Justin you know is often
more of a solo flyer and does better
that way too but I think that for me
like I've just decided I'm going to stop
attempting to go into events solo
unless for some reason you know like I
pre-hacked and I found a bunch of bugs
and I think like this is the one to make
the run for MBH on or something.
I I think that for me personally I just
like had that light bulb moment in the
same way Justin doesn't want to talk to
me more. I don't want to do solo events
anymore. Yeah, that's very good man.
Brandon I'm I'm curious are you an an
introvert or an extrovert?
>> [snorts]
>> My I would say
very much
>> I don't know. I think it depends on who
you ask. I'm very
I have some funky wiring I would say so
I'm not I don't know how to answer that
question.
>> usually the best way to answer it. When
you leave a social gathering are you
like oh man I need to rest I'm a little
worn out or do you get home and your
mind's buzzing like holy crap I wish I
could have hung out for another three
hours with those people?
No no no rest. Okay, yeah. Okay. Rest
rest. So maybe a little little bit on on
the line but definitely on the introvert
side. I think it's very rare. I'm
squarely in the introvert category
but like I think it's pretty rare to see
like a solid like solid extrovert you
know
do well in in this industry because it's
it is kind of lonely you know so you
definitely got something special going
there reso. Uh
>> Yeah, thanks. I mean I do think that
there's like a power in that so if
there's anybody out there who feels
extroverted and feels like they're a
little they're struggling like I just I
have used it to like I just have like a
mapping of like hey these people are
good at these things in my head and I
just message friends like even when I
got started I've noticed you know fav
he's going to love getting shout out on
this f a v fav up and coming young
hacker and he is so networky right he
finds a cool lead and he messages all of
us right he finds a cool bug he tells
everyone about it and I think that this
is actually a good way to use
extroversion as a way to kind of like
level up because you get feedback and
you get network you get connections like
I messaged him like I was hacking
Microsoft whenever they dropped that new
thing where they're paying for all
criticals and I like I fuzz them
overnight and like I sent him the leads
right cuz I know he hacks on Microsoft
and he like he's always already
messaging me and so it just kind of like
pays off to be like talking to people
all the time. Totally. Yeah.
No I do agree yeah after a 30 seconds of
reflection I'd probably say I fall more
into the introvert bucket like it's been
it takes a ungodly amount of energy from
to force myself to post on like socials
and things. Actually talking to people
like you guys and networking's fine but
like
>> [snorts]
>> I need to be compartmentalized and have
like my me time for a day when there is
no talking and nothing going on rather
than just me in the zone. I need that
>> that's that's the ticket right there
though because like if you're an
introvert you you need energy you know
you get energy from spending time alone
right if you're an extrovert then you
get energy from being with other people
so like a lot of people think it's about
like oh do you enjoy being social? No
that's not it. It's where you get your
energy from so if you're spending time
like alone needing to reset you know
that sort of thing after a lot of social
interaction then
it's probably a little bit more
introverted is at least that's my
understanding. Yeah, that's how I
understand it too. Yeah. Then yeah I'm
definitely on the introvert side for
sure. Yeah, I think I think for me as
well just looking at automation and
organization
having notes notes plus plus and Kaito
this year super helped me just being
able to take notes directly from replay
like with a key binding super helpful.
I've kind of got JX Scout and some AI
stuff built built up which is really
nice.
And
>> That's good. I think my organization on
my POC server could be a little bit
better. It's not very good there but it
gets the job done
and then as far as automation goes I
mean this last quarter with shift agents
like doing their thing I think I'm going
to be like super powered manual hacker
in in 26 for sure
using that so
just this past like case study that I
did
just like blew my mind and it's going to
completely change the way I hack I
think.
You got to remember to do it. That's the
thing. That's what I needed to do.
That's what's Yeah, well I've got the
muscle memory for it now too which is
which is good like I just got the key
binding set up and like you know
like I know what kind of stuff shift can
handle versus stuff I need to do myself
and I know how to give shift to the
tools it needs to be able to like
reproduce the things that I want it to
reproduce so a lot of the volume goes to
shift now and and I get to focus a
little bit more on the anomalous stuff.
Yeah.
It does raise a question and I just
thought about this speaking to you guys
as like we sort of grow and progress and
as the community levels up as hackers is
is automation simply going to be a new
name for remembering to like capture all
that context in a prompt? Is that just
going to be automation to an extent
moving on because like
I don't know.
>> the way Justin said it. I like the way
he said it
AI powered manual hacker cuz I think
that's more of what
he's doing and I think that that's like
where it's going to shine in 2027
or in 2026. Like I think maybe in 2027
or 2028 and beyond we might have more
AGI type hacking but I think like
Justin's big finding was because he
pointed at a specific thing right he
knew on this subdomain this thing is a
little bit unique compared to the rest
of the scope that I normally hack on and
he even told it what type of bug class
to look for on that on that cookie name
right and so I think like that type of
him using his expertise to know where to
look and then giving the AI the ability
to try lots of things which would save
him so much time is really why those
types of things worked out for Justin.
So I think
no I think when I think automation
Brandon I still think of like stuff
running over on my VPS right I would say
I would say what Justin labeled there is
what I would call like you know AI
powered manual hacking or whatever.
Yeah. So for the for the sake of this
conversation would you say that comes
under organization and like where
I'm trying to find a mental model where
it fits in the works
It's automation. It's AI automation AI
automation.
>> [laughter]
>> No,
it's definitely still automation guys
like a computer's doing the work like
Yeah, it's like manual automation rather
than full scale automation or something.
Yeah, but I mean you would still
consider like you know if you had like
four or three bypassers or something
like that that that's automation it's
still the same thing you know like
I mean is is freaking fuff animate you
know automation like yeah it's
automation so what's the difference
between shift? I mean it's using an LLM
they're all just you know matrix
multipliers. It's it's all it's all
automation but the the the you know the
there's definitely a difference between
hardcode and AI stuff. I mean if we want
to differentiate there and I think like
you said there's two main boosts that AI
bring brings allowing us to create
better hardcode right and then also
being able to use the AI to actually do
the hacking itself so yeah.
Um
All right. Good stuff.
>> Let's let's look at these next couple
metrics. Um
how much time can you put into bug can
you put into bug bounty? Where's your
motivation at? Uh actually we'll we'll
stick with those two first so like
for me personally I probably only have
like 20 25 hours a week of of effort and
time I can put into you know bug bounty
on average probably maybe closer to 25.
Um
but
not a ton of time right now with with
other ventures that I want to be doing
the lifestyle that I want to live you
know spending time with my wife and kids
you know, boundaries on my work life.
Yeah, I think that we're just
personally, you know, in the familial
environment right now we're we're trying
to do some things that take time and are
challenging
um
with parts of our family and I think
that's going to come first and then, you
know, I obviously I've got hardcore
commitments to like Caido and and CTBB
and then, you know, bug bounty is going
to be a massive part as well, but it's
probably only going to look like 25
hours or so.
Yeah, before I'll I'll go next just cuz
it's a hard ditto. I mean, I'm in the
same situation as you, right? Yeah,
yeah, we got kids, busy doing advisor
stuff. I'm almost exactly the same,
right? 20 25 hours I think.
And honestly, I just wonder if that's
like a hard max for me. Like I think
it was kind of, you know, maybe slightly
less, but that's what I was doing when I
was full-time or whenever I was like
working full-time somewhere else. And I
also find myself when I tried to do more
than that feeling like a little burned
out or just like, you know, mindlessly
watching YouTube videos. So like I think
that like that is like uh such a sweet
spot for me personally in that amount of
hours.
Yeah. Yeah, [snorts] I would and I done
some reflection on this at the start of
this month. Mine I couldn't even give
you an average. It's so all over the
place, like really all over the place.
And then I got into the
into the questioning of do I need to be
more disciplined around what I'm doing,
but then I had a counter argument with
myself that this is the bug bounty
lifestyle. You can do what you want.
What's your actual goals? So basically I
was arguing with myself. I must have
looked crazy if you drove past me, but
yeah, I don't know I don't know. I don't
know how many hours unfortunately. I
really have thought about this, but I
even asked my partner as well. It just
bounces so much depending on if there's
events, what's I think there are weeks I
put in 60 hours, you know,
I don't think it goes over 60, probably.
Yeah. 60 hours is more than people
think.
Like you know, I had to actually work 60
hour weeks whenever I was in a previous
job a few years ago and it's it's a lot
more than you think.
Yeah. Yeah, I think there are days
during the Life Hacking events when I'm
really really really going ham and the
family stuff is going okay, you know,
where I can put in 60, you know,
probably 10 it would probably be six
10s, you know.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
But very rare, you know, and then the
rest of the time it's it's much lower
for me.
Yeah, I would I would say when I'm doing
those longer stints I'm starting to get
all sorts of weird problems now that I
never used to get when I was younger.
Like my eyes literally cannot focus if I
do over 10 hours. Like I come out and
I'm partially blind a little bit. So I'm
a little bit more conscious of things
like that.
But yeah, I I agree.
Yeah.
Well, let's do these rapid fire since
we're running a little over time. Get
through a bunch of That's true.
Yeah, I I guess give me a quick metric
on y'alls motivation levels right now.
Like obviously you guys both had some
sick years, you know, how are you guys
your motivations going up right now?
What are you Where you at, Brandon?
Yeah, yeah, it's definitely on the up. I
mean, when I sat down last week and
looked at some of my stats and spoke to
Reza and Monke briefly about some of
these things, I was like, you know what?
All in all,
this has been fantastic and I found that
doing stuff outside of bug bounty, but I
like hacking such security adjacent,
definitely fill up another bucket which
fuels this bucket. So I'm I'm
I'm going to tap into that more, but
yeah, man, I just want to I just want to
plan some stuff.
Yeah. Yeah, I mean, same. I just like
I'm extremely grateful for this year.
Every time I think about it, I try to
rest in that gratefulness because it's
so easy to run past it. As like highly
ambitious people, it's so hard to just
like, you know, be content.
And so I think I feel that exact way,
right? It's like what I the the good
stuff that has happened this year has
drove me to even more of it and then
also just being ambitious. I'm like, oh,
I need to do more. I want to do more.
And so yeah, I definitely I'm stoked to
do a lot more hacking, a lot more AI
stuff, a lot more automation. Like it's
hard during this downtime like during
breaks. Like I'm trying to take these
these these couple of weeks off. I think
you are too, Justin. And it's like I'm
just itching to be hacking. Like I'm
just itching to be on my computer to
like find bugs, build stuff, do things.
And that's exactly where we want to be,
right? You know, and that is exactly
where we want to be. With with, you
know, the Fronz episode back in the day,
one of the things he said that was one
of the key drivers for him was when he's
right about to find something, right
about to pop something, he closes the
laptop and walks away. And then he
he teases himself, you know, and makes
him like, you know, desire to come back,
you know, with more passion and energy.
And yeah, I think that's I think that's
the kind of energy you got to bring into
these breaks. Like man, like let's go
get it after we after we get back. I
will say I freaking love bug bounty. It
is it is
you know, super amazing and I'm very
passionate, very motivated right now for
it. For the first time in my life this
year, I think I found something else
that I love.
And that's product, guys.
I I really like designing products and
and I've been getting a little bit of a
taste of this with Caido and and
building out Shift a little bit. And I'm
like, man, I would really like to be
head of product somewhere.
So
I don't know, man. I like
>> to do it for your own product. You can't
just go get hired to be head of product
somewhere. No, no, I I think so. I I
think I think I could go either way.
Head of product, I mean, if you if you
find a product you really love, right?
Like Caido, for example, you know, it's
not my product, but it is like, you
know, my baby, you know, I love it,
right?
So I would like to be head of product
somewhere at some point. I don't know if
it's that's something I do this decade
or if I do it, you know, in the future.
But I
>> I will I will say in case in case this
does
affect some future timeline you're on,
Justin, I will say
I'm also an advisor for Caido, you know,
just claiming for everyone. Seeing how
Justin is an advisor makes me think that
he would be incredible head of product.
You are way more in the weeds than it
makes any sense
from like a financial perspective. I
don't understand how you care so much. I
care a lot. I love Caido. I use it all
the time. I love those guys. They're my
friends. I care a lot. And somehow
Justin cares like five times more. He's
like asking like intimately deep
questions of the Caido team and like
intimately like questions about the
product and I just don't even understand
how your brain got there, let alone does
it make any financial sense given
everything that is a part of that
decision. And so anyways, yeah, I think
that it I think that I have seen that
passion, I guess I should say, in the
last few advisor meetings. Thanks, man.
I appreciate that and I I and I really
do. Yeah, totally. It doesn't make any
sense, but I love it and and so I'm
going to do it anyway.
So we'll see. We'll see where that
lands, but I I love like
just working on the user experience and
obsessing over the user experience
inside of an app. Like I think that is
super fun.
So yeah.
We'll see We'll see where it goes, but I
just want to say like I don't think
there's anything that I've ever that's
really actually made me think like, ah,
maybe I'd rather do this than than bug
bounty. And this is the first time like
that thought Interesting.
Which is kind of crazy. And it cuz cuz
it does scale a little bit better, too,
right? Like bug bounty, surely
certainly, you know, I could build
automation, make it scale a little bit
better.
But bug bounty, you know, you're doing
the work manually and it's work that you
love, so you can't complain, but it
doesn't super scale. Being head of
product and having equity in a in a
startup would would scale. So
interesting thought there. I know we
we're short on time.
I just want to
ask
and Reza, if you have to drop, that's
fine, too, and and Brandon and I can
close out the episode, but
what are your overall goals for bug
bounty in general? Like what is Why are
you doing bug bounty and and what
um
Yeah, what what do you want out of it?
And I'll answer first so you guys have
some time to think. But for me,
I want to find cool volns and achieve
mega impact. Like I just I love the
technical challenge of it. I love the
fact that I can say, wow, I just hacked
that company and like now I'm looking at
somebody else's PII. Like this is crazy.
Um
I want to do bug bounty within my my
defined work hours. I don't want to let
it run over my whole life like I did in
the past when I was a younger hacker.
Um I want to not be consumed by it, but
let that that distance, right? Like that
not being consumed
fuel the the fire even more, you know,
and just have this kind of tug, you
know, relationship with bug bounty.
And I want to have fun with my
colleagues, right? Like I want to spend
time with other smart people that are
going to make me better as a hacker and
I feel like I have a great way of doing
that in the bug bounty world.
Yeah, so I would say my goals are, you
know, obviously pretty similar.
The first is just like the most metrics
based one is just like keep the current
pace of earnings. Um
You know, I I just want to have another
year like I did this year. It's, you
know, it's fantastic. I don't feel the
need to like massively jack it up or
anything, but if I made the same amount
this year as I do or next year as I did
this year,
I think that would be incredible.
Definitely continue to prioritize faith
and family and like you said, work
within those work hours. I, you know, I
have made that a goal this past year and
basically stuck to it. It was a part of
kind of the, you know, the deal with my
wife with going full-time was that it
would stay between those cuz it is so
easy to be like, I could just go make
more money. I could just go make more
money. Um and so I think that's cool.
And then I just want to do cool stuff
worth talking about. Like, you know, the
I think the mantra for everyone should
be do do cool stuff do cool stuff and
tell people about it and that's like the
best way to kind of succeed as a human
and also not just succeed. Like success
isn't the end all be all, but I think
also just have a high level of
satisfaction with your with your work.
And I think
yeah, I think so, you know,
for you obviously it's like finding
crazy bugs. I think for me it is, too,
but I think like just do cool stuff this
year. Whether that's,
you know, finding crazy bugs or whether
that's finding crazy collaborations or
building crazy automation that finds
cool bugs, just like do cool stuff
that's worth talking about. Mhm.
Brandon.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, for me
I feel like I really like the aspect of
growing technically in bug bounty. So,
like
I know we'll give some context to the
listeners and viewers, but when we first
started our mentorship, Justin
client-side was like
unfathomable for me. Like it was just
like why did why? It's like why? How?
Um
and I was very much a server-side guy
and not that that didn't treat me
like good. I found a lot of really cool
server-side bugs there.
But um the technical aspect of growing
with bug bounties like only last month
it must be or the month before I started
learning mobile hacking and on this I
just had my first mobile paid out as a
high. Yeah.
>> 4K. So, like that that growing and the
the
the personal challenge of growing and
think doing things that I didn't think I
could do before does a lot for me as a
person. That's inside a bug bounty, but
also outside. Um so, that's good.
And other than that, I just maintain a
good level of earnings to give me the
flexibility to explore other things I
also enjoy doing. Yeah, that makes
sense, man. What what what kind of bug
was it in the mobile? So, it was a bit
of a it was a bit of a funky one. Um so,
essentially there's an insecure
deep link handler which could allow me
to inject something to then attack an
AI. I will say no more. Mhm, very
>> Because I it's private, but
>> I love it, man. I love it. Um all right,
so uh Reza, I want to be respectful of
your time. Um
at the end of this episode we were going
to do our you know, call our shot for
the next year, right? With some of these
some of these goals. Um
And we also wanted to do uh predictions
for the upcoming year and that's sort of
thing. Sweet.
>> Um do you want me to run down these?
Yeah, why don't you try to hit all of
these and then if you need to drop you
can and then Brandon and I will go back.
My family's here, but I will do this in
the next few minutes and then drop. So,
they'll be fine.
Who would I like to collaborate with? I
would love to continue to collaborate
with all my good friends. So, I'm just
going to name someone that I haven't
collaborated with that I would love to
and that'd be Matt Brown. I think it'd
be really fun to do something hardware
related. I know you and I and him will
hopefully pull something off the next
year.
I would like to continue to spend you
know, 25 hours per week. In general, I
think that making better use of my time
would be an insane would be like a
really great goal, right? And I think
that that would be fixed by another
answer to one of these questions is by
having a better anchor program. Like
basically having something that I return
to. It's like I sit down in the morning,
check my messages and then I'll like get
to work on that program if I don't have
like an H1C or something else going on,
right?
>> [snorts]
>> And so yeah, I think that what
what I like to hack on, what program or
platform, I would like to have some
anchor programs. And so, you know,
probably will be Google Plus, you know,
two others or something, but uh I would
love to yeah, work with you on that like
even if you just want to like message me
once a month and be like, "Did you pick
one yet?" You know, or make sure you
spend time on the anchor program.
Um as far as hacker motivation, I think
just the same as this year, right? Just
like keep doing cool stuff and talk to
people about it and that'll stick. Money
I'd like to earn, I already mentioned
this is the same amount that I made this
year.
Um
how many bugs I would like to submit? Uh
I think um
yeah, I don't think that this is like a
good metric for me. I think more it's
like hours worked and like time in. Cuz
I don't you know, if I had submitted 160
like Brandon, I'd have been proud of it.
And if I'd made as much as I made this
year and I submitted 50 bugs, I'd be
proud of it. So, I don't I don't really
think that that like matters much to me.
I would love to eventually get on the
top 100 on HackerOne, you know, I think
being spread out and having bigger
bounties um and like a higher impact
score is good, but it would be awesome
to be on the top 100 for HackerOne cuz
like you said, I'm being in the top
like, you know, 1 or 2% of earners feels
amazing and actually is what matters to
my family. So, numbers are just numbers,
right? They're made up internet points,
but I would love to be on the the top
100 page.
Uh severity distribution, I don't really
care. I like finding highs and crits,
but it doesn't matter that much to me.
And oh, research. I would like to
publish some research on markdown to
HTML impact like research specifically
from like an AI perspective. I've been
working with Valentino and BusFactor on
this and we haven't made anything
publishable or even really that
actionable. So, I think that that would
be one thing I would love to do for you.
>> I want to see that on the lab, man. I
want to see that on the lab website.
>> Yeah, it needs to be on there. I mean,
yeah, it should be already. So, anyways,
that's it.
>> Okay, good stuff, man. Did you have any
like predictions for 2026 you wanted to
shoot out or or you want to leave that
to us? Mhm.
I do think that 2026 could be the year
of the AI assisted manual hacker and I
think that
with the latest shift and shift agent
being stable, I think that that is
something that is going to be massive
this year both for the community and for
you and I. Um
and I don't know if I have any other big
predictions. I think that you know, 2025
was supposed to be the year of agents
and it really was. I mean, people
adopted cloud code and codex en masse
and that was really awesome. Um so,
yeah, I don't know. I yeah, I don't
think that I have any other like crazy
predictions. Mhm, very good, man. All
right, well we'll we'll we'll try to
lose
>> Merry Christmas. Happy New Year,
everyone. It's been an incredible year
and I'm excited to keep doing it. So,
peace out, guys.
>> Thanks for joining us today, man. Bye.
Um
all right, Brandon. Um yeah, let's kind
of work through this same the same thing
he had here
uh and kind of go through each one of
these ourselves. Um the first ones are
are like what are some areas you would
like to grow as a hacker? And for me
um I would like to be a little bit more
reactive when stuff are is released that
I should I could go hack on. I I think a
lot of times I have my plan and I when
you know, some opportunity comes up like
either I don't have the flexibility in
my life due to like, you know, family
stuff or other things to go like
reactively hack on it. Um
or you know, I've just got my like thing
I'm hacking on right now and I'm like,
"Ah, I can't be pulled away." And and
this whole react to shell thing um kind
of slipped by me uh
cuz of the timing with family stuff that
was going on. But I would love to be
able to react to that and and jump in on
those opportunities this year.
Yeah, 100% um
so, for me I it's interesting cuz like
my next year goals always start in
December a little bit because I I'm all
pre-planning. I the same happened last
year. I was pre-planning how to message
No, the year before I was pre-planning
how to message you and all sorts. Um but
for me like mobile hacking I've recently
started doing because I think it's a
really nice peripheral scope increaser
and like in one of the most recent
events I've done, I submitted mobile
bugs and outside of that event I've
submitted mobile bugs. So,
peripheral scope is definitely something
I want to improve on mobile in that
aspect.
And I've been doing a load of AI this
year. I feel like
that's something I want to maintain and
if I can increase in terms of
throughput, definitely a lot of that
because yeah, it's uh
it's where Well, I mean, it's just so
nice to hack. It's fun to hack and
everyone has something. I don't know,
man. I just I don't find it that fun to
hack, to be honest. It's getting more
fun to hack now, you know, with these
sandboxes that are hooked into um and
all the tools and stuff like that. I
just like
I don't know, man. I just I like
something
I like something a little bit like
meatier, I feel. Like it and a little
bit more deterministic. But I I I agree.
I mean, there is really fun AI scope,
especially when it integrates more
traditional aspects of computing like
file systems or like, you know, database
connections or, you know, HTTP
interaction, something like that. Um so,
yeah, I I I could definitely see that.
Um but that's definitely not my my like
go-to focus for this upcoming year.
Um
as far as people the next one on the
list here was who I'd like to
collaborate with. Um not going to try to
list everyone, but I have enjoyed these
collabs this year. Mattias, Franz,
Shubs, Great Me, Reza, Access has
Doctor, Lupin, and Monke. Um and if I
left you guys out, I'm so sorry. These
are just the ones I rattled off my head
when I was prepping. Um but it's been a
fun year for collaborations. I think I
learned a lot. I'm still going to
continue doing my solo thing and then
collaborate when it makes sense, but um
those are kind of the ones that I had in
in my list. Um oh, and Bus. Bus, of
course. Yeah, Bus is a blast.
>> How could you miss Bus, man? I know,
dude. What am I doing? I got to add I'm
going to put him in right here. No one's
going to know. The the the document's
going to reflect it, too.
>> [laughter]
>> Um yeah.
Yeah, [snorts] for me I would say the
client-side gang, pretty much a lot of
the people you just listed from the CTB
I've collabed with, I have good
relationships with. We have a lot of
fun. There's a lot of knowledge transfer
there as well.
So, with those guys, I think as well if
it comes up
I did do a small collab with Franz,
Shawn Jay, Mr. Jonathan Bauman and um
and those guys in the event. If I can
collab with them more, that'd be great.
Um
just such a high level and high caliber
of just like militant poning. It is
fantastic to see. Um Ben is well. Namsac
is another guy I'd like to collab with.
At but he yeah, at
is where we done an event together. I'm
just trying to get all the names up
together. See, here's the thing as well
what I mean about growing as a hacker.
I didn't do much collaboration at the
start because I was still like very
unsure if I could deliver value in a
collab and like I was still going
through that process of like coming to
terms with bug bounty full-time.
Now I would say next year will probably
be a lot more collab um now I've sort of
gone through that journey. So, That
sounds great, man. I'm excited for that.
Um
as far as uh the next question is how
many times per week would I like to
hack? For me, I would like to hack 32
hours a week. I probably will try to set
a minimum around around 20 and I'll
probably hit around 25 again. Um but
yeah, I would love to work on, you know,
bug bounty hunting more. It's just stuff
gets in the way. Um yeah, what what
about you? Where where would you like to
How many hours would you like to put
into bug bounty ideally?
Yeah, I think a good spot would be 5 to
6 hours a day cuz sometime I'm I do
that cuz sometimes I end up accidentally
doing some stuff on the weekend as well.
[__] nice sniped. Mhm. And alongside
obviously you yourself have various
other projects and income streams that
you need to work on. Um as do I. I'm
building them out. So, I think that will
put me in a good spot to give me a
little bit of flexibility with the other
ones as well. Nice. That's good. I think
as far as managing hacker motivation,
which is the next one, um
I think prioritizing other things
outside of bug bounty
will
increase that yearning, right? Like we
talked about for for bug bounty. So, I
think that'll be good. Um as far as
money I would like to earn, I'm going to
keep it at the same amount that I did
last year. I missed I was under my my
stretch goal by like 5% and I might make
it this year. If if some of the crits
that I have right now pay out, we'll see
um
inside this year, but most of the people
are off for the rest of the year in the
US. So, I doubt they'll pay out. Um
but it was it was a it was a fun year
for that and I'm going to keep the the
that target at around the same.
Um and I kind of agree with Rezau. I'm
not sure the like number of bugs I would
like to submit is a great metric, but I
would kind of like to see that go down
and the earnings stay the same
or or go up.
Right? I feel like that would be be kind
of um fun to see. So, around 100 uh is
probably about good for me,
um but I would like the earnings to
either go up or stay the same. Um so,
and then I'm passing that off to you,
Brandon. That is
hacker motivation. How do you plan to
manage that this year? Um if you would
like to say, you know, ranges or give
some rough estimate on how much you
would like to earn and then how many
bugs you would like to submit.
Yeah, hacker motivation. I touched upon
this earlier, but recognizing now that
buckets adjacent to bug bounty
>> Mhm. um
that are still sort of related really do
a lot.
Because I I go somewhere, I speak about
bug bounties, some of the bugs I've
done, some of the cool stuff I'm doing,
or I speak to someone that's really
interested in bug bounty or runs a
security program or a CISO with problems
and I'm just like, "Ah,
there it is again. Just the urge
to hack something." It just comes back
and strikes. So, that's a big one for
me.
So, I'm definitely going to step and
stack going into next year. How much
money would I like to earn? So, from bug
bounty alone, I would like to keep that
at the same level that I have done
this year.
With the caveat of increasing my other
income streams. And just for everyone
listening, I pretty much
overdone my two goals that I've done. I
I crushed them both.
Um in hindsight, maybe I set things a
little bit too low, but um my earnings
goals got well and truly beaten the crap
out of, which is good to say, fantastic
to say.
Um and bugs submit, I mean,
I'm not even going to comment on this
one because I try and adapt to the
target very much. So, if that means I do
a lot of volume and not much impact
based off of the the decision and
constraints I'm in, so be it. Um I have
no problem with that. Now, I'm not
precious about it.
Mhm. Um
But yeah, that's what I would say. That
sounds good. All right, last couple
questions and then we finish the
marathon of uh of the personal hacker
inventory. Um
what platforms or programs would you
like to hack on? What automation would
you like to hack on or like work on?
What research would you like to do and
how would you like to contribute to the
community? Um for Yeah, go ahead.
So,
programs. I As from my previous
episodes, I do have a hit list that I
keep up to date, a hit list of targets
that I'd like to hit and that's very
much still under under works. What I
would say is the notable one that will
be a next year's target is Google for
sure. It has to be. I have to do it now.
I'm getting um I don't get FOMO often,
but I'm getting FOMO
with Google. So, I'm going to hit that.
With automation, I'm going to continue
building out some of my frameworks I've
done. You will have access to one of
them soon, very soon, um to try it out.
And also carrying on the vibe coding.
And I will say as well
codifying my knowledge into prompts a
little bit more to do more things with
Shift. I'm going to put that under
automation because I it is in a sense
automation that you need to sort of
crack. Mhm.
Mhm. Totally.
Um I think for me the platforms and
programs I would like to hack on, I I'm
pretty
pretty pleased with what I've got with
um
uh you know, Capital One, Epic, Google
and some Amazon.
Um
I would like to try T-Mobile this year.
I've heard a lot of people having
success on T-Mobile. So, that one could
be kind of interesting. Um I am US-based
so that I can go like, you know, get one
from the store and like set it up pretty
easily, which is good. Um so, I think I
might try that. Automation is going to
be largely Shift Agents for me this
year, I think. Uh
and I'm not sure I'm going to do much
else from an automation perspective. I
don't plan to go back into the recon
game. I was thinking about it, but I
think probably not. Um
As far as research goes, I really
enjoyed that New Relic thing. Like that
was really fun. And I think I will try
to do more client-side research if I'm
going to do research. Um And then as far
as contributing to the community, I
think I'm just going to keep on doing
the podcast, man. The podcast is like,
you know, I think about all I can manage
from a contribution perspective to the
community. And I'm going to keep
obviously working with Caido, releasing
plugins, crafting that product to serve
the community in that way.
Um
And I think that's about all I've got on
the docket. I think that'll keep me
plenty busy for 2026. Oh yeah, man.
Absolutely. Absolutely. I think
research-wise, it will be bug bounty-ish
for me. What I would want to do is
release some research under my company,
however, because that's a very good
it's a double header. It's research I
get to perform and do and it's also
marketing material which I get to
represent under my company for some
certain things. I've got some things in
the notepad. When I'm off, I'm going to
I'm going to about some bounce some
ideas around and see what I come up
with. Yeah. The other thing I would like
to do is I would like to do another
enterprise app.
Um like
zero-day search really quickly. I was
talking to somebody in the CTBB
community about like that whole Grafana
thing I did back in 2020.
And I had a lot of fun with that. So, I
might do that again. I might just pick
like a a high target, you know,
like often found across the bug bounty
scope, um you know, enterprise app.
Grab the source code, reverse it, try to
find a unauthenticated zero-day. I think
that'd be pretty fun. Just just as like
a a fun thing. Um
As far as predictions for the upcoming
year goes,
um I think that
I I I agree with with um Rezau that
Shift Agents and, you know, hacker
supplemented or yeah, AI supplementing
manual hacking is going to be
a a necessity by the end of 2026, I
think. Um
And Shift is going to need to grow a
little bit as a product, I think, but
before then. Um but I think it's 90% of
the way there right now. And and uh I've
already had really good success with it.
I plan to continue using it. Um
I think source code review is going to
change a lot, too.
Uh um
client-side source code review with, you
know, Cloud Code or Gemini or whatever
it is, uh I think will will really be
super helpful this year.
Um
Yeah, besides that, I I don't really
have any other massive massive
predictions. I think the bounties will
continue to go up uh overall. I think um
bug bounty isn't going anywhere.
Um do you have any thoughts for
predictions for the next year?
Yeah, I feel So, I was listening to a
podcast about how
Cloudflare have now entered the browser
game a little bit and how they're
fundamentally
all Cloudflare customers are turning off
access to AI crawlers and they're
monetizing it um where
content creators get paid for their
content in another way. And how they've
open-sourced this agent-to-agent
payment system. Um
I think that
as we progress and we sort of hit that
critical mass now a little bit with some
of these targets that we're hacking,
we are going to start to see a bit more
of this
third-party attack surface that we
haven't really had to see before,
whether that comes in new protocols like
that, new MCP servers, and new like
AI-related integrations. So, if that's
your flavor of hacking and you enjoy
hacking stuff like that, keep an eye out
for it cuz I would expect to see more
things like that coming up. But like
I don't want to keep like saying, "Oh
yeah, I agree with what he said." But I
actually do agree with what you and
Rezau said about in terms of like the
hacker
behavior, I'd say. I'm very much in the
same boat on. Yeah. Yeah, I think that's
I think that's a no-brainer. I think we
will start seeing, you know, we already
saw Expel kind of do their run this
year, but I think I I would also predict
that probably this year
we will see, you know, a
a like bug bounty hunter created
autonomous, you know, AI hack bot
essentially start really really really
getting some crazy results. We've seen
that a little bit already, actually. Um
some of the niche members of the CTBB
community have shared some success with
hack bots they've created, but I think
we'll see something really really start
to climb the leaderboard in a meaningful
way this year.
Um
Yeah, and I I think
the other prediction that comes to mind
is that I think it will actually get
harder than it already is to compete in
the recon games because with that with
the the presence of vibe coding, you
know, changing who can create
automation, I think that we will see
more competition even than we have in
the past there. So,
the people that are winning in that
arena will be the people with access to
custom bugs, right? You know, bugs that
other people aren't looking for. So,
it's going to become a lot more of a
research game.
And and you know, one of the things we
have done a little bit with CTBB is try
to, you know, encourage pairings between
recon hackers and, you know,
researchers. Um
and I think that would be another really
fun thing to push this year in the CTBB
community is like, okay,
let's try to get let's spend a couple
weeks trying to find, you know, cloud
misconfigurations, you know,
enterprise software misconfiguration,
something that is like not a zero-day,
but is like a common misconfiguration
that we can hand to the recon guys and
get like, you know, a split on
to generate passive income moving
forward.
Yeah, I think that I think cuz I think
the recon part of that though is going
to become a lot less valuable because
more people are going to be able to do
it because of the the vibe coding. So, I
think splits for recon boys will
probably be forced down from a market
perspective
due to more supply in the market.
Agreed. Yeah, it's very and like you
only have to go into the CTB channel and
like it feels like the amount of tools
and tips and like all these little
things that have been vibe coded
extensions, burp extensions, they're all
just coming out so much quicker
and
like it's it's reducing friction on my
platform. So, yeah, I'd agree. I'd agree
with that. Very nice. All right, man.
That was a a marathon episode. My voice
is about to give way. I was just like
coughing a lung out while I'm mute while
while you're answering that last
question. But, um that is a wrap on 2025
critical thinking. Thank you guys so
much for listening this year. It's been
amazing. Our viewership has been very
supportive. We brought on Brandon as a
co-host.
We'll see you guys in 2026.
See you in 2026.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content
>> [music]
>> or if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/discord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great high-level discussion
happening [music] there on top of
masterclasses, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. [music]
It's a great time, trust me. All right,
I'll see you there.
It's hard not to just keep talking about
stuff, but it's like, oh, it's off the
air. I got to wait.
>> I'm like, have you seen the meme of the
guy when he has the veins popping out of
his
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> [gasps]
>> You're like,
That's exactly how I feel right now.